[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Kyle：回叫L的第二个租户。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: The second tenant of call back L.
好吧，我将从根本上声明或断言回调是不合理的。
Well, I'm gonna fundamentally declare or assert that callbacks are not reasonable.
我强调说建议我的意思不是在某种意义上合理的理由
And I highlight reason to say suggest I don't mean reasonable in the sense
很讨人喜欢。
of like likeable.
我的意思是合理的，他们不能被推理。
I mean reasonable, they are not able to be reasoned about.
让我试着举例说明。
Let me try to illustrate.
你们中有多少人以前听说过
How many of you have ever heard before or
以前对自己说过，我是一个一心多用的人？
said before to yourself, I'm a multitasker?
以前有人这么说过吗？
Anybody ever say that before?
这很常见。
It's pretty common.
人们都在谈论，我在街上开车，我在电话里聊天
People talk about, I'm driving down the street, I'm talking on the phone and
发短信，我把笔记本电脑放在我旁边的座位上，听着收音机，还有
texting, I have my laptop in the seat next to me, and listening to the radio, and
妈妈在打电话。
Mom is on the phone.
在多任务处理方面做了一大堆事情。
Doing a whole bunch of stuff on multitasking.
那简直是胡说八道。
Well that's nonsense.
我们并不是真正的一心多用的人。
We're not actually multitaskers.
在我们最高的认知水平上，
At our highest level of cognition,
这是我现在唯一关心的部分。
which is the only part that I care about right now.
我不是神经学家，所以我不是真正的神经学家。
I'm not a neuroscientist, so I'm not really speaking as a neuroscientist.
但从我所知道的和我们所观察到的来看，
But from what I know and from what we can observe,
在我们最高的认知水平上，我们的大脑基本上是单线程的。
at our highest level of cognition, our brains are fundamentally single threaded.
在任何给定的时刻，我们的大脑只考虑和
At any given instant our brain is only thinking about and
认知地思考一件确切的事情。
cognitively thinking about one exact thing.
我们大脑的许多其他部分都在照顾一些其他的部分
Plenty of other parts of our brain are taking care of all the other out of some
比如我们的心和呼吸以及所有其他的东西。
of things like our heart and breathing and all that other stuff.
我不是在说那个。
I'm not talking about that.
我说的是最高层次的认知
I'm talking about the highest level of cognition the part where we
有意识地计划和思考事情。
are intentionally planning and thinking about things.
在那个时候，我们只想着一件事。
And at that part we're only thinking about one thing at that exact moment.
所以，让我们想象一下今天早上当你们都醒来的时候。
So, let's imagine this morning when you all woke up.
今天早上你心里想，我必须计划好我的一天。
This morning you thought to yourself, I gotta planned out my day.
所以，当你醒来的时候，你开始计划一天，就像，我要去喝点咖啡，
So, when you woke up, you started planning a day like, well I got to get some coffee,
我去洗澡。
and I'll hop in the shower.
然后我会上车开车去上班然后我会去看这个
And then I'll get in the car and drive to work and then I'll head over to this
研讨会，你以非常有序的一步的方式计划你的一天。
workshop and you planned out your day in a very sequential step by step fashion.
实际上，我们所有人的大脑都会说这是我们的大脑在工作，
Virtually all of us our brains would say that's our brains work,
我们以非常有序的方式思考事物。
we think about things in a very sequential fashion.
然而，我也愿意打赌你们中几乎没有人
However, I'm also willing to bet that virtually none of you
让你的早晨完全按照你的计划进行。
had your morning play out exactly the way you planned.
你在煮咖啡，然后你妈妈打电话来，所以你被打断了
You were up making some coffee and then your mom called, so you got interrupted by
那个电话不是计划的一部分然后发生了其他的事情
that call that wasn't part of the plan and then this other stuff happened and
你的车没油了，你的计划必须改变。
your car was out of gas and your plan had to change.
谢天谢地，当你妈妈打电话给我的时候你没有，
And thankfully you didn't have when your mom called me like,
这是我没有计划的一整天的拍摄。
well there's the whole day shot I didn't plan for that.
所以，我最好还是回去睡觉，明天开始吧。
So, I better just go back to bed and start of tomorrow.
谢天谢地，你的大脑很有趣，就像JavaScript引擎一样，
Your brain thankfully is interesting a lot like the JavaScript engine,
因为它可以在事件方面被中断。
in that it can be interrupted event wise.
就像一个事件，你可以有一个事件火，它可以选择一个公正的回应。
Like an event, you can have an event fire and it can choose to respond in a just.
但这不是我们关心的部分，我们在这里关心的部分
But that's not the part we care about, the part that we care about here
是我们认知的一部分，我们在那里计划事情。
is the part of our cognition where we planned things.
从根本上说，我要争辩的是我们自然而然地计划事情
And fundamentally, what I'm gonna argue is that we naturally plan things and
顺序同步一步的方式。
sequential synchronous step by step fashion.
所以，如果这是我们计划事情的方式，那也是我们编码的方式，最自然的。
So, if that's how we plan things, that's also how we code, most naturally.
现在我有了一个理论。
Now I have a theory here.
这不是一条法律，这是我所能得到的最接近被证明的法律。
This is not a law, it's as close to as proven a law as I can probably get.
我有这样的理论，任何我们大脑分叉的地方
I have this theory that any place where our brain diverges
从JavaScript引擎的工作方式。
from the way the JavaScript engine works.
在两人分道扬镳的那一刻
At that moment where the two diverged it is at
在我们的代码中发生错误的那一刻。
that moment that bugs happen in our code.
无论我们的大脑偏离JavaScript和你的方式。
Wherever our brains diverged from the way the JavaScript and yours.
我对JavaScript引擎的工作原理无能为力。
I can't do anything about how the JavaScript engine works.
这样我就可以教你更好的了，
It just works that way I can teach you better about it,
试着更好地训练你的大脑。
try to train your brains better.
但我也可以尝试为您提供一些模式，让您可以更自然地编程
But I can also try to offer you patterns that allow you to program more naturally
喜欢你的大脑，所以希望你的程序中有更少的bug。
like your brain, so that there are hopefully less bugs in your program.
这基本上就是我的教学理论。
That's basically my theory of teaching.
我如何训练你写代码，使它工作起来更像你的大脑
How do I train you to write your code, so that it works more like your brain so
更少的发散和更少的虫子。
that there's less divergence and less bugs.
所以，它更合理，更容易理解。
So, it's more reasonable, it's more understandable.
我们看到回调并没有以那种方式提供给我们太多的一致性。
We see callback don't really offer us much accordance in that way.
因为我们可以从伪任务的角度来思考
Because we could think about it from a pseudo task perspective
就像你知道我喜欢伪代码的什么？
like you know what I love about pseudo code?
伪代码很棒，因为你可以凭空发明神奇的东西。
Pseudo code awesome because you just get to invent magical stuff out of thin air.
我希望我能拿到钱整天写伪代码，
I wish I could get paid to write pseudo code all day,
因为这将是世界上最有趣的工作。
cuz it'd be the funnest job in the world.
我可以发明一些东西，比如在3号线上，我发明了暂停。
I get to invent stuff like on line three where I invent pause.
我调用的这个神奇的东西叫做暂停，它实际上并不存在，但是
This magical thing that I invoke called pause, which doesn't actually exist, but
这无关紧要，因为这是一个伪码。
it doesn't matter cuz it's a pseudo code.
然后，在线上是什么，
And then, on line what is it,
在第9行，我发明了另一个也不存在的东西，叫做简历。
on line 9 I invent this other thing that also doesn't exist called resume.
我只是神奇地从第3行停止的地方拾起，对吗？
I just magically pick up where line 3 left off, right?
这就是我用伪代码写出来的方法。
That's how I'd write this out in pseudo code.
但一旦开发商拿到它，
But as soon as a developer got hold of it,
他会说不，这个，你只是在胡编乱造。
he'd say no no no, this, you're just making stuff up.
事情不是这样的。
That's is not how it works.
所以，他们开始重新安排事情，然后
So, they'd begin to rearrange things, and
他们可能会像那样重新排列伪代码。
they might rearrange the pseudo code like that.
他们说，好的，我们可以做这个暂停和恢复的事情，然后暂停和
And they say well, we can do this pause and resume thing and then a pause and
继续，看看我们现在做了什么？
resume and see what we've done now?
我们已经开始实现这是一系列嵌套的回调。
We've started to implement this is a series of nested callbacks.
因为只有回调，这是我们表达和
Because callbacks alone that's the only way for us to express and
听着，这里有个别致的术语给你。
listen here's a here's a fancy term for you.
时间依赖性。
Temporal dependency.
当一件事依赖于另一件事在这件事开始之前完成，
When one thing depends upon another thing finishing before this thing can go,
这是一种时间依赖性。
that's a temporal dependency.
使用回调来表达时间依赖的唯一方法是嵌套一个
And the only way with callbacks for us to express temporal dependency is nesting one
在另一个内部，对一个内部的呼叫对另一个的呼叫。
inside of the other, the call to one inside of the call to the other.
无论我们是在行函数表达式中还是在行函数表达式中执行此操作
Whether we do so within line function expressions or
只有函数调用。
with just the function calls.
仅在回调中处理时间依赖的唯一方法是通过嵌套。
The only way to handle temporal dependency in callback alone, is through nesting.
为什么会有这样的问题？
Why is that such a problem?
它是这样一个问题的原因是现在你的大脑不能得到线性进展
The reason it's such a problem is now your brain doesn't get to linearly progress
通过密码。
through the code.
你的大脑必须做我称之为非局部跳跃的动作。
Your brain has to do what I call non-local jumps.
这里有个比喻给你。
Here's a metaphor for you.
你们中有多少人记得很久以前。
How many of you remember way, way back.
我说的就像80年代中期，原始的任天堂。
I'm talking like mid 80s, the original Nintendo.
而我最喜欢的游戏一直在原版，并进入塞尔达传奇。
And my favorite game of all time in the original, and into Legend of Zelda.
任何人都记得必须让这东西永远运转
Anybody remember have to leave the thing running forever and
玩它需要几个星期才能玩完任何东西。
play it would take weeks to play through whatever.
你知道我喜欢那个游戏的什么地方，尽管有一部分你会去
You know what I loved about that game though there is one part you would go
进了一个山洞。
into a cave.
突然，屏幕就变得完全黑了。
And all of the sudden the screen would go completely black.
除了在林克周围的这个小圆圈里他举着火炬。
Except for this tiny little circle around link where he's holding his torch up.
在任何给定的时刻，你都可以看到地图的一小部分。
And you can see just a small little portion of the map at any given moment.
现在你可以移动整个洞穴的链接，你可以看到整个地图，但只有这个
Now you can move link all over the cave you could see the entire map but only this
一小圈一圈，你不能一下子看到整个事情。
little circle at a time you could not see the entire thing all at once.
这就是今天的JavaScript编程。
That's what modern JavaScript programming is today.
现代异步JavaScript编程。
Modern asynchronous JavaScript programming.
现在，这不是对任何一个人的敲打，听这个建议，
Now this is not a knock on any individual person listening to this to suggest that
你们根本就是个糟糕的程序员。
you are just fundamentally bad programmers.
我们都受到这种方式的限制，
We are all limited in this fashion,
在我们的程序中发生的异步流量控制的复杂性？
that the complexity of asynchronous flow control that happens in our programs?
您的团队中没有了解所有这些流程路径的开发人员。
There is no developer on your team that understands all of those flow paths.
只是这超出了我们的理解能力。
It's just it's beyond our capacity to understand.
你可能会得到第一步，然后第二步，然后第三步。
You might get step one, then step two, then step three.
但是一旦你同时完成了第一步，第二步和第三步
But as soon as you get like step one, two and three at the same time and
当这两个人完成了这里和那里的射击，你就完全迷路了。
when these two finish fire it off here and there, you're completely lost.
你只能理解你得到的这一小部分
You can understand only just this small little portion you get that and
然后你搬到这里，你明白这一部分。
then you move over here and you understand this part.
然后你搬到这里，你就会明白这一部分。
And then you move over here and you understand this part.
如果这些地方是回调跳来跳去的地方，那就是上天所禁止的
And heaven forbid when those parts are where the callbacks are jumping around
在你程序的文件之间。
between the files of your program.
而且你根本不能按照你的大脑工作的方式来规划你的程序。
And you're fundamentally not able to plan out your program the way your brain works.
因为单独的回调没有表达东西的方式，
Cuz callbacks alone don't have a way of expressing things,
以顺序同步的方式查看。
in a sequential synchronous looking fashion.
似乎几乎不可能做到这一点。
It seems like it's almost impossible to do it.
不是吗？这看起来不像是一只几乎是独角兽吗？
Doesn't it? Doesn't that seem like almost a unicorn
就像没有办法以同步方式进行异步编码。
like there is no way to do asynchronous coding in a synchronous fashion.
这就像是假的同时也是真的，这似乎是不可能的。
That's like having false be true at the same time, that seems impossible.
当不厌其烦地谈论这个建议时，其实是
When going all the trouble to talk about this to suggest actually it is
很有可能。
quite possible.
但这就是为什么我们需要更好的模式。
But that's why we need a better pattern.
因为我们要解决回调地狱需要做的是能够表达
Because what we need to do to solve callback hell is to be able to express
我们的代码以同步顺序的方式进行，就像我们的大脑思考的方式一样。
our code in a synchronous sequential fashion the way our brains think.
所以，当我们编写像我程序前半部分那样的代码时，然后是第二个
So, when we write code like that first half of my program then the second
我程序的一半。
half of my program.
我们对自己说，这就像阻塞了1000毫秒。
And we think to ourselves that it's like blocking 1000 milliseconds.
这在JavaScript引擎中并不存在，实际上我将
Which doesn't really exist in the JavaScript engines is actually I'm gonna
在那期间做一大堆其他的事情。
do a whole bunch other stuff during that.
但我们需要做的是恢复同步表达事物的能力
But we need to do is restore the ability to express things in a synchronous
顺序看起来时尚。&gt；&gt；Kyle：那是
sequential looking fashion. &gt;&gt; Kyle: That's
我们需要回叫地狱的另一部分
the other part of callback hell that we need to
修复，使我们的同步代码从根本上更合理。
fix to make our synchronous code fundamentally more reasonable.